Here is the article by the Japanese student about his personal experience.
Read the article.
A tidal wave.
I went to the beach with my friends last Saturday.
When we were playing on the beach, suddenly the water started to go away.
We heard people shouting.
They were telling us to run away from the beach.
A big wave was coming towards us.
We ran up the hill as fast as possible.
When I looked back, the whole beach and all the buildings below us were in water.
Many boats were damaged.
After the tidal wave passed, the police checked to see if everyone was okay.
They warned us to stay away from the beach for a few days.
They told us that there was an earthquake a few kilometers away under the sea, and it caused the tidal wave.
Luckily, no one was hurt or killed.
All of us were happy that we were safe.